我要来这里做个新目录
And I'm going to come in here and
I'm gonna make a new directory.
我要给这个人打个电话
I'm gonna call this one
build a nodejs-app.
把目录换到那里
And change directories into there.
我不知道我为什么要这么做
I don't know why I'm doing this
all from the command line.
您也可以从 " 文件资源管理器 " 中完全执行此操作。
You could totally do it from here,
from the File Explorer too.
我想让你在这里做个新文件
So the first thing I want you
to make a new file in here,
我想让你称它为 index.js 。
I want you to call it index.js.
我想让你到课程网页来
And I want you to just come over
to the course web page here.
我们要去建一个 Node JS App
We're gonna go into
the Build a Node JS App.
复制并粘贴这些内容。
And just copy and paste this.
就像我写的像世界上最喜欢的服务器一样
Like I wrote just like the most
like Hello World server ever.
离开伊塞林特没人在乎
Go away ESLint, no one cares.
这不是节点 JS 类，
This is not a Node JS class,
我不指望你能理解到船上的任何东西
I don't expect you to understand
literally anything on the board there.
这比有关节点的打包节点 JS 应用程序更多。
This is more about packaging Node JS
applications than it is about Node.
但是，可以说，它导入节点中的 HTTP 核心模块，
But suffice to say,
it imports the HTTP core module in Node,
创建一个服务器，它在每次接收到请求时都将控制台记录。
creates a server that it'll console
log every time it receives a request.
然后他们会用这个年龄的智慧回答用户，我的上帝，嗨。
And then they'll respond to the user
with this age old wisdom of, my god, hi.
然后在端口 3000上启动服务器。
And then it starts
the server on port 3000.
在 Fronend Masters上，有很多伟大的 Node JS 内容。
There's lots of great Node JS
content on Frontend Masters.
如果你想多了解这些东西一定要检查这些东西
So definitely check out that stuff
if you wanna learn more about it.
好吧如果你想看看就像我说的结点 index.js
All right, so if you wanna just see,
like if I say node index.js,
您可以看到服务器已启动。
you can see there's a server started.
如果我在这里说当地的 3000 人
And if I go over here and
I say local host 3000,
你能在上面看到的很很特别的是我的天啊
you can see up there very
tinily it says OMG hi.
你会看到它的接收请求两次
You'll see that as it said
receive request twice.
这是因为当浏览器打开网页时，它也会请求收藏图标，
That's because when a browser opens
a webpage it also requests the favicon,
所以才会有两次
that's why it's there twice.
我知道有人会好奇的所以这就是贫民窟
I know someone was gonna wonder
about that, so it's the favicon.
好的 Ctrl+C 以停止该问题。
Okay, so Ctrl+C to stop that.
允许使用包含此应用程序的 Docker 文件，并且
Lets make a Docker file that
containerizes this application and
然后为我们运行服务器，对吧 ?
then runs the server for us, right?
我现在想做的就是在同一个目录中创建另一个文件。
So what I wanna do now is I'm gonna create
another file in the same directory.
我要叫它 Dockerfile
And I'm gonna call it Dockerfile.
我想说你可以想象
I wanna say as you might imagine,
FROM 节点:12 - 拉伸。
FROM node:12-stretch.
我要说副本
I'm gonna say copy.
我们会把 index.js 复制到 index.js ，对吧 ?
And we're gonna copy index.js to index.js,
right?
把它从源头复制到目的地吧
So copy it from source to destination,
right?
然后我会说
And then I'm gonna say
命令节点 index.js。
command node index.js.
好了好了
There you go.
好了现在我要建码头了对吧
Okay, and
now I need to build my docker file, right?
所以我要在码头上建码头
So I'm gonna say docker build.
给它一个标签，所以 -t 而不是 --标记，如果你像我一样懒。
Give it a tag, so -t instead of
--tag if you're lazy like me.
我要用我的节点应用
And I'm just gonna stick with my-node-app.
这会覆盖以前的一切
This will overwrite
whatever was there before,
但我觉得我们可以把控制台记录在后面对吧
but I think we're okay to leave
the console logs behind, right?
我不知道有些人看起来很悲伤
I don't know, some of you look pretty sad.
因此， Docker 构建 -t my-node-app 和
So, docker build -t my-node-app and
那我们就放一段时间让它知道我们在这目录里
then we'll put period to let it know
there we're in this directory here.
你可以从节点上看到
And you can see there, from node,
在这里盖了个副本 CMD 好的
built that, COPY here, CMD here, good.
现在你可能在想，为什么把这些灰烬放在这里?
Now you might be wondering,
why is it putting these hashes in here?
因为每一个都在技术上是一个有效的容器
That's because every one of these is
actually technically a valid container at
每一个级别对吧
every single level, right?
所以我可以在我来之前先执行这个
So I actually could just execute
this one before I got here.
这就是 Docker 进行高速缓存的方式
And that's the way that Docker
does its caching is like,
好吧这是一个有效的容器
okay, this is a valid
container up to here.
如果你只在这里换东西，就从这里开始，对吧 ?
And then it just starts from here if
you only change things in here, right?
因此，如果我不更改 index.js，那么它将再次从该点重新启动，对吗 ?
So if I don't change index.js, it would
just restart from that point again, right?
所以这就是那些数字的原因。
So that's why those numbers are there.
我们将更多地了解 Docker 文件的最佳实践，但对于
We'll get more into best
practices of docker files, but for
现在才知道这就是为什么
now just know that that's
why those are there.
[ SOUND] 所以现在我可以说 docker 运行我的节点应用程序。
[SOUND] So
now I can say docker run my-node-app.
你开始了，服务器开始了，对吧 ?
There you go, server started, right?
因此，我们的节点应用程序现在正在容器中运行。
So our node app is now running
inside of a container.
但问题是，如果我来这里，它说无法连接。
Problem though, if I come over here,
it says unable to connect.
那为什么呢 ?
Well, why is that?
我们不跟它分享网络对吧
Well, we didn't share the network with it,
right?
所以记住了名字空间，对，刚才我们说的那个东西呢 ?
So remember name spaces, right, that thing
that we talked about a little while ago?
它被有意地限制在外面的世界。
It's intentionally limited
off from the outside world.
我们没有给这个容器明确的允许与主机网络通话
We did not give explicit permission to
this container to talk to the host network
所以它都包含在里面
so it's all contained inside of it.
它正试图伸出来，但主机操作系统就像
And it's trying to reach out but
the host operating system is like,
不你不能在港口里说话
no, you don't get to talk in that port.
那就这样吧
So let's do that.
让我们把它处理好
Let's make it work on that.
这是另一个我忘了告诉你的有趣的事情。
Here's another fun thing that
I forgot to tell you about.
请尝试按下 Ctrl+C 。
Try hitting Ctrl+C.
这就是我以前所讲的
This is what I was telling before.
节点不响应这些进程。
Node does not respond to
these sort of processes.
所以我要说的是 Ctrl+C to docker，
So what's happening is I'm
saying Ctrl+C to docker,
Docker 会把它传递到节点，节点就像我不在乎，对吧 ?
docker is then passing that along to node,
and node's like I don't care, right?
你可以在这里做一些事情。
So there's a couple of
things you can do here.
最好的做法是，您应该进入节点应用程序。
The best thing to do is you should
go inside of your node application.
同样，这不是一个节点课程，所以我不会给你们展示如何去做，但是
Again, this is not a node course so I'm
not going to show you how to do it, but
你会说， process.on，
you would say, process.on,
SIGTERM，对，然后你就会经历这些事情。
SIGTERM, right, and then you would go
through and do all that kind of stuff.
现在不做了
Not gonna do it right now.
但对于节点开发者，这是正确的方法。
But that's the correct way to do this for
a node developer.
所以我要做的第一件事是，让我们停止这一切，因为它必须停止。
So the first thing I'm gonna do is, let's
actually stop this because it has to stop.
所以我要说停手
So I'm gonna just say docker ps.
你可以在这里看到我的节点应用程序。
And you can see here
my-node-app right there.
pedantic_goldstine，请 Docker 杀死 pedantic_goldstine。
pedantic_goldstine, please docker
kill the pedantic_goldstine.
所以现在如果我回到这里，你会发现它已经消失了，对吗 ?
So now if I go back over here,
you'll see that it's gone, right?
接下来我要告诉你，如果你用 Docker 运行 -- init，
So the next thing I'm gonna show you,
if you run this with docker run -- init,
它的模块叫做 " 蒂尼" ， " T-I-N-I " ，它是向后的，对吗 ?
this runs up with it module called tini,
T-I-N-I, which is init backwards, right?
所以它会让你和你的人
And so it kind of proxies that process and
then it will shut down for you and
它会自动关闭您的节点。
it will automatically shut down node for
you.
所以如果我再这样做，然后按 Ctrl+C，蒂尼就会进入
So if I do this again with that and
I hit Ctrl+C, tini will actually go in and
为我杀死节点进程。
kill the node process for me.
所以这有点像个我不用去的小黑
So it's kind of like a little
hack that I don't have to go and
处理那些 sig 术语事件。
handle those sig term events.
它会为我做的
It'll just do it for me.
所以你会开始看到我运行这个 --init ，很可能 --rm 现在，就为了
So you'll start seeing me run that
--init and probably --rm now, just for
纯粹的懒惰是我不想自己去做的
pure laziness factor,
that I don't wanna go do that myself.
你可以在生产中运行
You could run this in production.
如果你真的想和蒂尼一起生产
If you really are gonna run it in
production with tini with a --init,
我建议去你的 Docker 文件安装蒂尼
I would suggest going into your
Docker file, installing tini and
然后从蒂尼执行节点，以便将其构建到 Docker 容器中。
then executing Node from tini so that it's
just built into the Docker container.
否则，您将会运行某些生产服务器，并且
Otherwise you'll forget,
you'll run some production server and
你不能把它关掉
you can't shut it down.
有点问题对吧
Kind of a problem, right?
所以现在我想把那个港口曝光对吧
So all right, so
now I wanna expose that port, right?
我想穿过那个集装箱
I wanna punch a hole
through that container so
我可以把 3000 口暴露给外面的世界
that I can expose that port
3000 to the outside world.
所以我要做的就是公布
So what I'm gonna do is
I'm gonna say --publish.
我想去港口 3000 我想把它暴露在 3000 的港口对吧
And I wanna take port 3000,
I wanna expose it on port 3000, right?
我可以在 8000 号端口上进行路由和曝光，但我不会去做。
I could do some routing and expose this on
port 8000 right, but I am not going to.
因此，如果我运行此服务器，请启动端口 3000。
So now if I run this
server started port 3000.
现在你可以看到它又说了，对吧 ?
And now you can see here it says again,
omg, right?
而且它说收到的请求，等等。
And it says request received,
so on so forth.
我们这样做的方式是发布 3000:3000。
And the way that we did that
is by the publish 3000:3000.
>> 所以，你不把它放到 c 线里吗 ?
&gt;&gt; So you don't put in a dockerfile
you just put it into the c line?
>> 所以我认为下一节是关于，好吧，有个东西叫
&gt;&gt; So I think literally the next section
is about, well, so there's a thing called
所以您可以在 Docker 文件中输入命令来执行该操作。
expose and so you can put a command
inside of docker file to do it.
但我建议通过发布库来做更多的事
But I would suggest doing it through
publish cuz it's something more you wanna
在运行时确定
determine at runtime and
只会让大多数人期待的工作曝光
expose just a necessary work
that most people expect it to.
所以，让我们一起去吧，但问题是好的。
So, let's just go with no,
but good question.